Joshua Medina

Senior Airdrop Rigging Operations Manager



Highly motivated, detail oriented, US Army veteran always seeking personal and professional growth and challenges. Has successfully worked with minimal supervison for the past 5 years as the only Senior Parachute Rigger in Qatar. Served 10 years in the US Army, serving all roles and responsibilites, culminating in being second in command of a detachment of personnel, and achieving numerous awards and promotions ahead of peers.

Professional Experience

Senior Airdrop Rigging Operations Manager

Qatar Emiri Air Force

May 2018 - Present

- · Solely responsible for effectively establishing the first and only airdrop rigging facility for the Qatar Armed Forces with zero supervision
- Ordered, received, inspected, placed in service, maintained, and repaired aerial delivery equipment ensuring 100%
- · Coordinated training for civilians and military members within the Qatar Emiri Air Force resulting in numerous personnel being certified to conduct airdrop rigging
- · Conducted inspections and maintained records of all airdrop loads used in airdrop missions resulting in zero malfunctions or incidents
- · Coordinated rigging and training operations of numerous personnel in different countries for Multinational Military

Senior Noncommissioned Officer In Charge

· As second in command, I coordinated the training requirements and certifications of all personnel in support of military operations for sole rigging facility of the United States Armed Forces in South West Asia

- Supervised and ensured rigging operations were conducted in accordance with all applicable policies and regulations resulting in 100% mission success
- · Conducted periodic inspections, packing, and rigging of United States government equipment to ensure complete
- Planned and executed joint operations between numerous armed forces branches of the United States and foreign allies

824th Quartermaster Detachment, US Army

June 2016 - October 2017

Parachute Rigger, 92R

United States Army July 2008 - June 2016

- · Inspected, packed, and repaired life sustaining equipment to include main and reserve parachute systems and parachute harnesses with zero deficiencies
- Planned and supervised training exercises for peers and subordinates alike

Education

Associate in General **Studies**

Central Texas College at

Killeen, Texas

August 2011-December 2013

Diploma Atlantic

Community High School

at Delray Beach, FL

August 2004 - May 2008

Key Skills

- · Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, and PowerPoint
- · Capable of working with little to no supervision
- · Extremely detailed oriented

Certifications

February 2009 US Army Parachute Rigger, 92R October 2014 Advanced Leadership Course November 2016 Military Free Fall & RAM Air Certified